Niko T. Cudiamat

Contact Numbers: 09958807850/366-4729 Email Address: nikocudiamat@live.com

PERSONAL SUMMARY

I am a self-taught software developer possessing over three years of experience in software application development and web/mobile development. I am committed to clean design and clean code with self-motivation to a high standard as well as the desire to learn new or old ways to develop an app or website. And also, being flexible on what the company need.

WORK EXPERIENCE

AiPayGo, Inc.

Republisys, Inc.

iOS Developer / Front-End Web and Mobile Developer

Pasig City, Metro Manila
Pasig City, Metro Manila
Jan 2019 to present

Amplified eSolutions, Inc.
Digital 2wist, Inc.
Multimedia Designer/Developer

Quezon City, Metro Manila Quezon City, Metro Manila Sept 2016 to Dec 2018

Responsibilities:

iOS Developer:

- Assists the lead developer and or developers in analysis, design, development, and performance optimization of web application
- Partner closely with product management, QA and your development team members to continuously improve our app
- Eager to get nerdy about memory management, UI layout and rendering, or network performance
- Act as technical lead on projects, assist with defining the solution, and working with a team of developers
- Work alongside other engineers and developers working on different layers
- Work closely with other Product Development teams to improve consistency and timing of releases
- Eager to get nerdy about memory management, UI layout/rendering and UI/network performance
- Parsed JSON responsive to represent data visually in charts and graphs, using Alamofire
- Created views and linked outlets using Storyboard, based off wireframe

Web/Mobile Developer:

- Oversees design and development of client websites.
- Conducts preliminary discussions with clients regarding design and functionality of website.
- Collaborate with designers to create clean interfaces and simple, intuitive interactions and experiences.
- Performs research on website design and development requirements.
- Ongoing design and maintenance of new and existing websites.
- Creates web applications to support website functions.
- Testing websites for functionality in different browsers and at different resolutions.

- iOS App Development
- Front-end Web and Mobile development
- Swift Language
- Coding & Programming
- UX and UI Design

- Web content management
- Video Editing
- Photo editing
- Video/Photo Shoot

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology - Digital Arts Far Eastern University Institute of Technology

2013-2016 Sampaloc, Metro Manila

KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Swift Language
- API Integration
- iOS Unit Testing
- Angular Framework
- Ionic Framework
- Wordpress
- Adobe Photoshop Pro
- Adobe After Effects Pro
- Adobe Premiere Pro
- Gsuite

PROJECTS under AiPayGo, Inc.

iOS Projects

- RealMark (Real Estate App for iOS Platform)
- PhonePera (e-wallet for iOS Platform)

Website

- GroovenStyle (Digital Fashion Showroom Website (WordPress and Angular) www.groovenstyle.com)
- AiPayGo (www.aipaygo.com)
- Republisys, Inc (https://www.republisys.com)

PROJECTS under Digital 2wist, Inc and Amplified eSolutions, Inc.

- SMDC Pro (WebApp)
- Detailing App (Carrier and Condura)
- Carrier Website (Adobe Muse and Wordpress)
- 555 Fried Sardines Video Content
- SMDC DIY VideoContent
- SMDC 10
- SMDC Video Content
- Concepcion Industrial CorporationWebsite
- Primehomes Website

SEMINARS ATTENDED

- Detailing App Launch
- Amazon Web Services Partner Connexions
- Adobe Cloud Solution
- Certified Maya Autodesk Associate